<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="cfr.xsl"?>
<CFRGRANULE xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="CFRMergedXML.xsd">
  <FDSYS>
    <CFRTITLE>28</CFRTITLE>
    <CFRTITLETEXT>Judicial Administration</CFRTITLETEXT>
    <VOL>1</VOL>
    <DATE>2014-07-01</DATE>
    <ORIGINALDATE>2014-07-01</ORIGINALDATE>
    <COVERONLY>false</COVERONLY>
    <TITLE>Appeals from denials of requests for access to records.</TITLE>
    <GRANULENUM>16.45</GRANULENUM>
    <HEADING>Section 16.45</HEADING>
    <ANCESTORS>
      <PARENT HEADING="Title 28" SEQ="3">Judicial Administration</PARENT>
      <PARENT HEADING="CHAPTER I" SEQ="2">DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</PARENT>
      <PARENT HEADING="PART 16" SEQ="1">PRODUCTION OR DISCLOSURE OF MATERIAL OR INFORMATION</PARENT>
      <PARENT HEADING="Subpart D" SEQ="0">Protection of Privacy and Access to Individual Records Under the Privacy Act of 1974</PARENT>
    </ANCESTORS>
  </FDSYS>
  <SECTION>
    <SECTNO>§ 16.45</SECTNO>
    <SUBJECT>Appeals from denials of requests for access to records.</SUBJECT>
    <P>(a) <E T="03">Appeals.</E> If you are dissatisfied with a component's response to your request for access to records, you may appeal an adverse determination denying your request in any respect to the Office of Information and Privacy, U.S. Department of Justice, Flag Building, Suite 570, Washington, DC 20530-0001. You must make your appeal in writing and it must be received by the Office of Information and Privacy within 60 days of the date of the letter denying your request. Your appeal letter may include as much or as little related information as you wish, as long as it clearly identifies the component determination (including the assigned request number, if known) that you are appealing. For the quickest possible handling, you should mark both your appeal letter and the envelope “Privacy Act Appeal.” Unless the Attorney General directs otherwise, a Director of the Office of Information and Privacy will act on behalf of the Attorney General on all appeals under this section, except that:</P>

    <P>(1) In the case of an adverse determination by the Deputy Attorney General or the Associate Attorney General, the Attorney General or the Attorney <PRTPAGE P="299"/>General's designee will act on the appeal;</P>
    <P>(2) An adverse determination by the Attorney General will be the final action of the Department; and</P>
    <P>(3) An appeal ordinarily will not be acted on if the request becomes a matter of litigation.</P>
    <P>(b) <E T="03">Responses to appeals.</E> The decision on your appeal will be made in writing. A decision affirming an adverse determination in whole or in part will include a brief statement of the reason(s) for the affirmance, including any Privacy Act exemption applied, and will inform you of the Privacy Act provisions for court review of the decision. If the adverse determination is reversed or modified on appeal in whole or in part, you will be notified in a written decision and your request will be reprocessed in accordance with that appeal decision.</P>
    <P>(c) <E T="03">When appeal is required.</E> If you wish to seek review by a court of any adverse determination or denial of a request, you must first appeal it under this section.</P>
  </SECTION>
</CFRGRANULE>
